Frank C. Laubach Collection
Frank C. Laubach Collection
- Trustees
  - Meetings
    - 1967-1971, 9 folders (Box 144)
    - 1973, 2 folders (Box 145)
  - Meetings, general papers, 1957-1972; undated (Box 145)
  - Memos to, 1960-1971 (Box 145)
  - Minutes of meetings
    - 1955-1967, 2 folders (Box 145)
    - 1968-1970 (Box 146)
  - Minute index (Box 146)
  - Newsletters, 1966 (Box 146)
  - President's reports to, 1961-1971 (Box 146)
  - Proposals to (Box 146)
  - Proposal to from the executive director (Box 146)
  - Recommendations by (Box 146)
  - Reports to
    - Annual, 1960-1970 (Box 146)
    - General
      - 1955-1971 (Box 146)
      - Undated (Box 147)
    - International projects, 1958-1970; 2 folders (Box 147)
    - Semi-annual, 1962-1970; 2 folders (Box 147)
    - United States programs, 1960-1971 (Box 147)
- Administrative files
  - Administrative papers
    - Accounts (Box 148)
    - Affiliation, agreement of, undated (Box 148)
    - By-laws, 1955 (Box 148)
    - Contracts
      - Banking, 1955-1963 (Box 148)
      - Leases, 1963 (Box 148)
      - Publishing, 1950-1968 (Box 148)
    - Contributions
      - General, 1956-1965 (Box 148)
      - Lists, 1957-1960 (Box 148)
      - General (Box 148)
      - D'Oliviera, Louise (Box 148)
      - Church, total U.S. (Box 148)
    - Copyrights (Box 148)
    - Development
      - Bulletins and reports, 1967 (Box 148)
      - Canvassing, 1967 (Box 148)
      - General
        - 1958-1967, 2 folders (Box 148)
        - 1968-1970 (Box 149)
      - Laubach Literacy Advance, 1966-1967 (Box 149)
      - Midwest (Box 149)
      - Red Cross (Box 149)
      - Reports, 1967 (Box 149)
      - Survey material (Box 149)
    - Director of education reports, 1963 (Box 149)
    - Ditto masters, miscellaneous (Box 149)
    - Executive Committee
      - Meetings, 1968-1971 (Box 149)
      - Memos (Box 149)
      - Recommendations, 1964-1969 (Box 149)
    - Form letters, 1961-1970 (Box 149)
    - Form letters, prints, sample (Box 150)
    - Foundations
      - Carnegie Endowment for International Peace (Box 150)
      - David C. Cook Foundation, 1968-1969 (Box 150)
      - Direct Relief Foundation (Box 150)
      - Foundation for World Literacy (Box 150)
      - General (Box 150)
      - General Telephone and Electric Fund (Box 150)
      - Investors Overseas Services, 1965-1967 (Box 150)
      - Johnson Foundation (Box 150)
      - Kellogg Foundation, 1964 (Box 150)
      - Kresge Foundation, 1963 (Box 150)
      - Lilly Endowment, 1964-1967 (Box 150)
      - Ottinger Foundation (Box 150)
      - Philco-Ford (Box 150)
    - Functions, departmentalization of (Box 150)
    - Fund applications, support for cooperative research, 1963 (Box 150)
    - Fund associates (Box 150)
    - Fund raising
      - Banquets, 1964-1968 (Box 150)
      - Churches (Box 150)
      - Laubach Literacy Advance, 1967 (Box 151)
    - Fund raising guides and information, 2 folders (Box 151)
    - Grants and scholarships
      - Applications, 1961-1968 (Box 151)
      - Fund records, Summer Institute of Literacy, Chautauqua (Box 151)
    - Incorporation, certificate of (Box 151)
    - Incorporation, certificate of, amendments, 1960 (Box 151)
    - Information about Laubach Literacy, general (Box 151)
    - Interim Committee, 1968-1969 (Box 151)
    - Internal organization recommendations (Box 151)
    - Inter-office memoranda
      - 1954-1961 (Box 151)
      - 1962-1965 May, 5 folders (Box 152)
      - 1965 Jun-1967 Jun, 4 folders (Box 153)
      - 1967 Jul-1968 Mar, 5 folders (Box 154)
      - 1968 Apr-1970, undated; 5 folders (Box 155)
    - Interoffice shipping, 1965 (Box 155)
    - Inventory of equipment and furniture, 1965 (Box 155)
    - Investment Management Account, Marine Midland Trust (Box 155)
    - Job descriptions (Box 155)
    - Label listing (Box 156)
    - Library, Laubach Literacy (Box 156)
    - Long-range plans, Laubach Literacy, 1967 (Box 156)
    - Management information (Box 156)
    - McMillan Company (Box 156)
    - News releases (Box 156)
    - Notes, general (Box 156)
    - Organizational charts (Box 156)
    - Permissions, reprint (Box 156)
    - Personnel
      - Applications, confidential
        - A-M, 3 folders (Box 156)
        - N-Z, 2 folders (Box 157)
      - Applications, tabulation of, 1961-1963 (Box 157)
      - Biographical sketches (Box 157)
      - Director of education, 1961 (Box 157)
      - Director of programs (Box 157)
      - Employees, lists of, 1962-1968 (Box 157)
      - Gipson, Priscilla (Box 157)
      - Graduation, employee (Box 157)
      - Information, general (Box 157)
      - Job descriptions (Box 157)
      - Laubach, Robert, biographical notes (Box 157)
      - Morrill, Louise D'Oliviera (Box 157)
      - Roberts, Byron T. (Box 157)
      - Shumate, Hazel (Box 157)
      - Status reports, employee, 1968 (Box 157)
    - Planning: publishing (Box 157)
    - Pledges, delinquent (Box 157)
    - Policy
      - "Each One Teach One in Action," R. S. Laubach, 1968 (Box 157)
      - Foreign work (Box 157)
      - Use of name by affiliated organizations (Box 158)
    - Policy and planning, 1965-1969 (Box 158)
    - Printing techniques (Box 158)
    - Procedure, office (Box 158)
    - Programs, summary of (Box 158)
    - Promotion
      - Budget, 1967 (Box 158)
      - "Christian, Save Your World", 1970 (Box 158)
      - Church programs (Box 158)
      - Goals and materials (Box 158)
    - Promotional ideas (Box 158)
    - Promotional materials
      - Exhibits (Box 158)
      - Information, 3 folders (Box 158)
      - Information (Box 159)
      - Mailing ideas, 2 folders (Box 159)
      - Testimonials (Box 159)
    - Proposals for headquarters building (Box 159)
    - Public relations, church (Box 159)
    - Publications
      - "Laulitgram", 1965 (Box 159)
      - "News," Laubach Literacy, 1969-1972 (Box 159)
      - "Newsletter," Laubach Literacy Fund, 1956-1967 (Box 159)
      - "Newsletter," production of (Box 159)
      - "Newsletter," recipients of (Box 159)
    - Publishing (Box 159)
    - Sponsors, 1963 (Box 159)
    - Staff meetings (Box 160)
    - Staff meetings, minutes, 1962-1967 (Box 160)
    - Syracuse University, MEMOS from (Box 160)
    - Tape recordings and slide shows, projects (Box 160)
    - Thirtieth anniversary dinner participants (Box 160)
    - Valuation of assets, 1966 (Box 160)
    - Washington office (Box 160)
    - Washington office, Board of Zoning adjustment (Box 160)
  - Administrative correspondence
    - [General]
      - 1959-1962 Apr, 6 folders (Box 161)
      - 1962 May-1963 Dec (Box 162)
      - 1964 (Box 163)
      - 1965 Jan-1966 Mar (Box 164)
      - 1966 Apr-Dec (Box 165)
      - 1967 Jan-Nov (Box 166)
      - 1967 Dec-1968 Dec (Box 167)
      - 1969-1970, undated (Box 168)
    - Financial contributions
      - 1960-1963, 2 folders (Box 168)
      - 1964-1969, 4 folders (Box 169)
    - Grants and scholarships, 1954-1969; 2 folders (Box 169)
    - Personnel, 1946-1969; 2 folders (Box 169)
    - Personnel: Mason, David, 1968 (Box 169)
    - Requests for financial support, 1960-1963 (Box 170)
- Financial papers
  - Account diversification, 1968 (Box 171)
  - Accountants' reports, 1956-1969; 13 folders (Box 171)
  - Balance sheets, 1957-1959 (Box 171)
  - Balance sheets and income statements, 1964-1967 (Box 171)
  - Bank statements
    - 1960, 1962-1964, 4 folders (Box 171)
    - 1965-1968, 6 folders (Box 172)
    - 1968-1969, 2 folders (Box 173)
  - Banking agreements (Box 173)
  - Banking resolutions, corporate, 1969 (Box 173)
  - Budget, 1956-1957; 1960,; 1962-1969; 8 folders (Box 173)
  - Budget appropriations, 1969-1970 (Box 173)
  - Checkbooks
    - 1958-1961, 2 folders (Box 173)
    - 1964-1968, 5 folders (Box 174)
    - 1966-1969, 3 folders (Box 175)
  - Currency exchange, 1964-1967 (Box 175)
  - Estate settlement, 1968 (Box 176)
  - Expenses, 1961-1968 (Box 176)
  - Finance, report of the director of, 1962 (Box 176)
  - Financial report on literacy courses, 1958 (Box 176)
  - Financial statements, 1956-1960 (Box 176)
  - Foreign projects (Box 176)
  - Funds received (Box 176)
  - Income and contributions (Box 176)
  - Income report (Box 176)
  - Income statements, investment portfolio, 1970 (Box 176)
  - Income tax, 1966 (Box 176)
  - Individual earnings records, 1966-1967; 2 folders (Box 176)
  - Insurance
    - 1963-1965 (Box 176)
    - 1966-1968 (Box 177)
  - Insurance policies (Box 177)
  - Investment, 1965 (Box 177)
  - Investment management, 1965 (Box 177)
  - Payroll
    - Publishing, 1963 (Box 177)
    - Records, 1968 (Box 177)
    - Summary, 1968 (Box 177)
  - Projects, overseas, 1962 (Box 177)
  - Publication costs (Box 177)
  - Reports, 1957-1958; 1960-1962,; 1964-1969; 3 folders (Box 177)
  - Salaries, 1962-1963 (Box 177)
  - Social Welfare Department (Box 177)
  - Stocks, 1957-1958 (Box 177)
  - Tax, state, general (Box 177)
  - Taxes, State of New York, 1965-1966 (Box 177)
  - Unemployment compensation, 1964-1966 (Box 177)
- Projects, domestic
  - Address lists, general, 2 folders (Box 178)
  - Adult Basic Education, general, 2 folders
    - Inter-university Workshop, 1965 (Box 178)
    - Regional conference, 1965-1966 (Box 179)
    - Workshops (Box 179)
  - Adult education, general summary, undated; 4 folders (Box 179)
  - Adult education legislation, 1967 (Box 179)
  - Adult literacy primers, revision of, 1969 (Box 180)
  - Adult readers book lists, 1964-1965 (Box 180)
  - Alabama, state literacy (Box 180)
  - Alphabet and spelling materials (Box 180)
  - Arithmetic, remedial, 1968 (Box 180)
  - Arkansas, state literacy (Box 180)
  - Articles, American education, 1958 (Box 180)
  - Asbury Seminary (Box 180)
  - Association Films, Inc. (Box 180)
  - Audio-visual communications, Laubach Literacy (Box 180)
  - Audio-visual equipment (Box 180)
  - Audio-visual materials, generation information for "Streamlined Reading"
    - 1-5B (Box 181)
    - 6-7B (Box 181)
    - 10-12B (Box 181)
    - 13-19A (Box 181)
    - 20-23A (Box 181)
    - 24-30A (Box 181)
    - 31-37 (Box 181)
    - 38-46 (Box 181)
  - Bible lessons (Box 182)
  - Bible story, pictures (Box 182)
  - Bible telecourses, 1962 (Box 182)
  - Bibliographies (Box 182)
  - Bibliography of Recommended Materials for Adults with Limited Reading Ability. Smith, Jeanette, undated (Box 182)
  - California, state literacy (Box 182)
  - Central Training Institute, U.S. Army (Box 182)
  - Charts and Stories record, undated (Box 182)
  - Chautauqua Institution, 1959-1964; 2 folders (Box 182)
  - Chinatown (Box 182)
  - Church literacy (Box 182)
  - Colorado, state literacy (Box 183)
  - Community action programs, 1966 (Box 183)
  - Companies of Compassion, accounts
    - General material, 2 folders (Box 183)
    - Membership and donation lists (Box 183)
    - Report, 1962 (Box 183)
    - Promotion of, 2 folders (Box 183)
    - State, 6 folders (Box 184)
  - Compassion Book, materials gathered for, 1953 (Box 185)
  - Connecticut, state literacy (Box 185)
  - Coordinating Committee guides, 1965-1967 (Box 185)
  - Corrections, Bureau of, Pennsylvania, 1962 (Box 185)
  - Course evaluation (Box 185)
  - Courses, assignments and projects, 1964
    - General (Box 185)
    - Literacy as Evangelism, 1962-1969 (Box 185)
    - Teacher training, 1965 (Box 185)
    - Teaching English and Simple Writing for New Literates (Box 185)
    - Techniques of Adult Literacy, 1961-1969 (Box 185)
    - Writing for New Literates (Box 185)
    - Writing Poetry (Box 186)
  - Demonstrations (Box 186)
  - Development, Companies of Compassion, 1968 (Box 186)
  - Diagnostic Reading Survey (Box 186)
  - Diagnostic Reading Tests (Box 186)
  - Diagnostic Survey for Beginning Adult Readers, Laubach (Box 186)
    - Experimental version, 1966 (Box 186)
    - Student answers, 1966 (Box 186)
  - Economic Opportunity Act, 1964 (Box 186)
  - Economy, world (Box 186)
  - Education and vocational programs (Box 186)
  - Education Bulletins, 1962 (Box 186)
  - Education Bulletins (New), 1-43, 1969-1970 (Box 186)
  - Education Directory: Cortright, Richard (Box 186)
  - Education Reports, stencils (Box 186)
  - Education, world, articles (Box 186)
  - Educational and Cultural Center Serving Onondaga and Oswego Counties (Box 186)
  - Educational Developmental Laboratories (Box 187)
  - Educational information (Box 187)
  - English Spelling Made Easy, 1959 (Box 187)
  - "Ergodic and Stochastic Principles in Relation to Laubach Literacy Materials" (Box 187)
  - Evaluation forms, various, 1966 (Box 187)
  - Evangelism (Box 187)
  - Exhibit materials (Box 187)
  - Experiences, evaluation (Box 187)
  - Field reports, Laubach Literacy Center, 1963 (Box 187)
  - Film scripts, production
    - Various (Box 187)
    - Various (Box 188)
  - Films
    - "Breakthrough in Hong Kong" (Box 188)
    - Miscellaneous (Box 188)
    - "Plight of the Desperate Billion", 1962 (Box 188)
    - Production, information re (Box 188)
  - Films, literacy (Box 188)
  - Florida, state literacy (Box 188)
  - Georgia, state literacy (Box 188)
  - Hartford Seminary (Box 188)
  - Hawaii (Box 188)
  - Health, Education and Welfare, U.S. Department of, Proposal to, 1963 (Box 188)
  - Home Economics, teaching: writing workshop, 1965 (Box 188)
  - Hong Kong Baptist College (Box 188)
  - Information on various fields (Box 188)
  - Information, general (Box 188)
  - Information sheets (Box 188)
  - Interview projects (Box 188)
  - International Teaching Alphabet (Box 188)
  - Itineraries, Johannes, Phyllis (Box 188)
  - Kansas, state literacy (Box 189)
  - Kentucky, state literacy (Box 189)
  - "Ladder of Literacy," Robert, R. S., 1964 (Box 189)
  - Language Facility Test, Dailey, John T., 1965 (Box 189)
  - Language Power Seminar, 1966 (Box 189)
  - Laubach Literacy Institute, 1962-1969 (Box 189)
  - Laubach Literacy School, 1961 (Box 189)
  - Laubach Literacy Summer Institute, 1968 (Box 189)
  - Laubach, Robert, literacy work (Box 189)
  - Literacy associates, United States (Box 189)
  - Literacy councils, general, 2 folders (Box 189)
  - Literacy education (Box 190)
  - Literacy evangelism (Box 190)
  - Literacy in the United States, general, 1960-1962 (Box 190)
  - Literacy Institute, Indianapolis, 1962 (Box 190)
  - Literacy Institute, University of Virginia, 1963 (Box 190)
  - Literacy kit (Box 190)
  - Literacy materials, lists of, 1960-1962 (Box 190)
  - Literacy organizations
    - Alabama (Box 190)
    - Alaska (Box 190)
    - Arizona, Tucson (Box 190)
    - Arkansas (Box 190)
    - California, Alhambra (Box 190)
    - California, Alhambra (Box 191)
    - California, Alhambra (Box 192)
    - California, Alhambra (Box 193)
    - California, Berkeley, 2 folders (Box 193)
    - California, Vista (Box 193)
    - Certification procedure (Box 193)
    - Colorado (Box 193)
    - Connecticut (Box 193)
    - Delaware (Box 193)
    - Florida, Miami (Box 193)
    - General (Box 193)
    - Georgia, Atlanta (Box 193)
    - Idaho, Boise (Box 193)
    - Illinois (Box 194)
    - Indiana (Box 194)
    - Iowa (Box 194)
    - Kansas (Box 194)
    - Kentucky (Box 194)
    - Maryland, Montgomery County, 2 folders (Box 194)
    - Maryland, Prince George's County (Box 194)
    - Massachusetts (Box 194)
    - Michigan (Box 194)
    - Minnesota (Box 194)
    - Mississippi (Box 194)
    - Missouri (Box 194)
    - Nebraska (Box 194)
    - New Jersey (Box 194)
    - New York (Box 194)
    - North Carolina (Box 194)
    - Ohio (Box 194)
    - Oklahoma (Box 194)
    - Oregon, 2 folders (Box 195)
    - Pennsylvania (Box 195)
    - South Carolina (Box 195)
    - Tennessee (Box 195)
    - Texas (Box 195)
    - Texas, Baylor Literacy Center, 2 folders (Box 195)
    - Texas, Houston (Box 195)
    - Virginia (Box 196)
    - Washington, D. C., 2 folders (Box 196)
    - Washington State (Box 196)
    - Wisconsin (Box 196)
  - Literacy organizations and information, 1959-1966 (Box 196)
  - Literacy programs, general (Box 196)
  - Literacy quarterly reports (Box 196)
  - Literacy report, United States (Box 197)
  - Literacy statistics (Box 197)
  - Literacy studies, Baylor Literacy Center, 1961 (Box 197)
  - Literacy Survey, 1966 (Box 197)
  - Literacy Symposium (Box 197)
  - Literacy teaching, 1964 (Box 197)
  - Literacy teaching, quarterly reports, 3 folders (Box 197)
  - Literacy training, Alabama, reports (Box 197)
  - Literacy Week, National essay (Box 197)
  - Literacy workers, handbooks for (Box 197)
  - Literacy
    - Adult, Materials and Programs, review and appraisal of (Box 197)
    - Articles re, 1955-1966 (Box 197)
    - General, 3 folders (Box 198)
    - Harvard panel on, 1970 (Box 199)
    - Information re (Box 199)
    - Standards for (Box 199)
  - Mailing lists, general (Box 199)
  - Manpower, general (Box 199)
  - Manpower Literacy Programs, evaluation of (Box 199)
  - Manpower retraining (Box 199)
  - Maryland, state literacy (Box 199)
  - Mass media (Box 199)
  - Massachusetts, state literacy (Box 200)
  - Michigan, state literacy (Box 200)
  - Migrant workers (Box 200)
  - Mississippi, state literacy (Box 200)
  - Mississippi Delta Project, 1964 (Box 200)
  - Model School Project
    - Program proposal, 1965-1966 (Box 200)
    - Training report, 1965-1966 (Box 200)
  - National Affiliation for Literacy Advance (NALA)
    - Conference, 1969 (Box 200)
    - "Leadership," NALA (Box 200)
    - Promotion (Box 200)
    - Questionnaire (Box 200)
    - Regional Training Conferences, 1966-1968; undated; 4 folders (Box 200)
    - Semi-Annual Reports (Box 200)
    - Survey (Box 200)
    - General information re, 2 folders (Box 200)
    - Study on, 1970-1972 (Box 200)
  - New Hampshire, state literacy (Box 200)
  - New literates
    - Information for (Box 200)
    - Materials for
      - "Anand the Wise Man," Laubach, Frank, second reader, Vol. I (Box 201)
      - "Anand the Wise Man," original copy (oversize) (Box 234)
      - Articles to be edited (Box 201)
      - "Be Informed" Series
        - [General] (Box 201)
        - Credit (Box 202)
        - Driving (Box 202)
        - Evaluation forms (Box 202)
        - Evaluations (Box 202)
        - You and the Law (Box 202)
        - You and Your Family (Box 202)
      - Bible Guide, Higby, E. J. (Box 202)
      - Bible Stories (Box 202)
      - Bibliographies (Box 202)
      - Books (Box 202)
      - Booklets, 1961 (Box 202)
      - Child care (Box 203)
      - "Citizens of God's World" (Box 203)
      - "City Living," Laubach, Frank and Kirk, E. M. dummies (Box 203)
      - Cleaning (Box 203)
      - "Easy Bible Guide," Higby, E. J. (Box 203)
      - Family planning (Box 203)
      - First aid (Box 203)
      - Follow-up books (Box 203)
      - Fundamental education (Box 203)
      - General (Box 203)
      - "Going Forward," word lists for chapters 1-13 (Box 203)
      - "Good Manners" revision (Box 204)
      - "Gospel of Luke, Simplified," Laubach, Frank, 1951-1953 (Box 204)
      - "Growing Old" (Box 204)
      - Health (Box 204)
      - "Heroes of Faith" (Box 204)
      - "Heroes of Witness" (Box 204)
      - Hobbies (Box 204)
      - Home Economics Workshop (Box 204)
      - Information re (Box 204)
      - "It is Smarter not to Drink" (Box 204)
      - "Juan and Marie Make a New Home" (Box 204)
      - "Learn to Pray" (Box 204)
      - "Learning to Read," Grant, Alice (Box 204)
      - "Letters to Grandma," Roxby, Mary Belle (Box 204)
      - "Literature," Meador, Murray (oversize), 3 folders (Box 234)
      - "Making Our World Safe" (Box 204)
      - Miscellaneous (Box 205)
      - "New Streamlined English Series," Readings in (oversize) (Box 234)
      - by New writers, 1961 (Box 205)
      - "News For You" (Box 205)
      - "News For You," goals for (Box 205)
      - Newspapers, 1964-1969 (Box 205)
      - "Our United States," Laubach, R. S., 1965 (Box 205)
      - "Our Fifty States," Schwartz, Lillian (Box 205)
      - "Read and Grow," Laubach, R. S. (Box 205)
      - "Read to Learn" (Box 205)
      - "Reading to Learn" (Box 205)
      - "Readings in Literature," Meador, Murray (Box 206)
      - "Readings in Literature," teachers' guides to, Meador, Murray (Box 206)
      - Recipes (Box 206)
      - Rejected stories (Box 206)
      - Religions (Box 206)
      - "Science" (Box 206)
      - Stories translated from Arabic (Box 207)
      - Stories, various, 2 folders (Box 207)
      - "Story of Jesus", 1946-1948 (Box 207)
      - "Story of Jesus"
        - Projects (Box 207)
        - Vernacular editions (Box 207)
      - "Story of Jesus retold from the Bible," books 1-12, Laubach, F., 1946 (Box 207)
      - Stories based on Streamlined English word lists (Box 207)
      - "Titus," translation of (Box 208)
      - "U Sein, the Wise Man," Laubach, F., 1948 (Box 208)
      - "We Honor Them", 1965-1968 (Box 208)
      - Word lists (Box 208)
      - Writing (Box 208)
    - Progress report of (Box 208)
    - Reading for (Box 208)
    - Writing for, 2 folders (Box 208)
  - New Readers Press
    - Contract for, 1963 (Box 208)
    - General information, 1966 (Box 208)
  - New Streamlined English series, development of (Box 208)
  - New York State literacy, 1968 (Box 208)
  - New York state literacy, adult basic education, 1965 (Box 208)
  - "News for You"
    - [General], 1960-1963 (Box 208)
    - Material for (Box 208)
    - Questionnaires 2 folders, 1968 (Box 209)
  - News stories (Box 209)
  - North Carolina, state literacy (Box 209)
  - Ohio, state literacy (Box 209)
  - Oral Roberts University (Box 209)
  - "Participants in Laubach Literacy Training Courses, A Study of," Dethe, S. K. (Box 209)
  - Peace, re, 1962 (Box 209)
  - Penitentiaries, state
    - Louisiana (Box 209)
    - Ohio, film literacy, 1960 (Box 209)
    - Literacy in (Box 209)
  - Pennsylvania, state literacy (Box 209)
  - Phonic methods (Box 209)
  - Population and birth control (Box 209)
  - Population statistics (Box 209)
  - Population, world (Box 209)
  - Poverty, suburban programs in (Box 209)
  - Press releases (Box 209)
  - Primers, illustrations (Box 209)
  - Printed material, demands for (Box 209)
  - Printing (Box 210)
  - Prisons and reformatories, state: state directors for adult basic education programs (Box 210)
  - Private enterprise, world wide, 1951-1956 (Box 210)
  - Program materials, miscellaneous (Box 210)
  - Programmed instruction (Box 210)
  - Programmed teaching (Box 210)
  - Programs, general (Box 210)
  - Project, needs re, promotion and report (Box 210)
  - "Pronouncing glossary," Laubach, F., 1968 (Box 210)
  - Proposals and models (Box 210)
  - Proposals and research, 1970 (Box 210)
  - Proposals by director of publication, 1962 (Box 210)
  - Proposals for financial aid (Box 210)
  - Proposals for National Association of Volunteer Adult Literacy Organizations, 1966 (Box 210)
  - Proposals, literacy, 1963-1965 (Box 210)
  - Proposals project, 3 folders (Box 211)
  - Proposals
    - To commissioner of education, 1960 (Box 211)
    - Educational television, 1964-1965 (Box 211)
    - Evaluation Study by Laubach Literacy (Box 211)
    - Literacy Workshop (Box 211)
    - Los Angeles County Adult Literacy, 1965 (Box 211)
    - Mississippi Delta Project (Box 211)
    - Research (Box 212)
    - Teaching "English the New Way," Experiment in, 1963 (Box 212)
  - Publishing: Behrman, Mayes, general (Box 212)
  - Publishing materials (Box 212)
  - Publishing records (Box 212)
  - Publishing reports (Box 212)
  - Puppetry (Box 212)
  - Questionnaires, 1967 (Box 212)
  - Readability formulas, Spache and Gunning (Box 212)
  - Readability Survey (Box 212)
  - Reading Ability, Durrell Analysis of (Box 212)
  - Reading Aids, unidentified (Box 212)
  - Reading instruction, articles re (Box 212)
  - Reading tests, Job Corps (Box 212)
  - Regional Training Conference, 1966-1967 (Box 212)
  - Rehabilitation programs (Box 212)
  - Reports, general (Box 212)
  - Reports, scripts for tapes (Box 213)
  - Reports on literacy, local (Box 213)